翻譯  衛老哥
翻譯  香茗小焙
翻譯  章魚X
翻譯  某豚
翻譯  小飯
翻譯  噎死青春
翻譯  澤川
時間軸  旅行的木訥
後期  餓得慌
特效  寶寶
顧問  老杜
校對  草草
總監  草草
紙牌屋
第二季  第五集
人人影視傾情奉獻
進來
馮先生  時間到了
一萬
走吧
向阿波馬托克斯最後的血腥進軍在這裏發起
Here began the last bloody march toward Appomattox
而格蘭特將軍與李將軍就在那裏首次碰面
where General Grant met General Lee for the first time.
勇敢的人們用鮮血鑄就歷史
And brave men bled, set the course of history.
我很榮幸能夠來到這裏
I'm so honored to be here,
紀念陸路戰役150週年
celebrating the 150th anniversary of the Overland Campaign.
感謝郡長羅伯茨
Thank you to County Administrator Roberts,
感謝所有熱忱的情景重現演員
to all the dedicated re-enactors,
當然  還要感謝
and, of course,
奧基弗州長組織了如此精彩的三日活動
to Governor O'Keefe for organizing such a wonderful three-day event.
說完了嗎  先生
Oh. That's all, sir?
說完了  短小精悍
That's it. Short and sweet.
至少很短小
Or at least it's short.
加夫尼的人稱內戰為"北方侵略戰爭"
In Gaffney, people called it the "War of Northern Aggression."
個人而言  我並不以南部邦聯為榮
I personally take no pride in the Confederacy.
打不贏的仗就不要打
Avoid wars you can't win,
更不要為奴隸制這樣愚蠢的原因而戰
and never raise your flag for a asinine cause like slavery.
-他就來  -好
- He's on his way. - Fine.
人們會忘記這事的
People will move on.
不會的  你說的越少  他們越會去挖掘
They won't. The less you say, the more they'll dig.
那就讓他們挖
Let them.
薇拉  能讓我們單獨待會兒嗎
Willa, could you give us two seconds?
我就在外面
I'll be right outside.
麥金尼斯的事發生在大學時期
McGinnis happened in college.
墮胎則是五年之後的事
The abortion happened five years later.
沒有留下任何病歷
There aren't any medical records.
完全沒有嗎
None at all?
我們特別確保了這一點
We specifically made sure.
護士呢  等候室的人呢
A nurse? Somebody in the waiting room?
只有醫生一個人在場
The doctor was the only one there.
那他現在在哪裏
Then where is he now?
已經是很久以前的事了  康納  他去世了
It's a long time ago, Connor. He passed away.
如果我都不擔心  那你也不必
And if I'm not worried, you shouldn't be.
就算如此  性侵的事現在成為焦點了
Even still, sexual assault is part of the conversation now.
所有的文章和專欄都會提到你
Every article and column mentions you.
如果我們不提供素材  就無法塑造你的形象
If we offer nothing, we can't shape your image.
我說的很清楚  我不想曝光
I made it very clear I don't want exposure.
等我們有新東西可說的時候  我們再說
When we have something new to say, we'll say it.
薇拉  參謀長聯席會議那邊怎麼樣了
Willa. Any luck with the Joint Chiefs?
主席辦公室還是說他沒空
The Chairman's Office still says he's unavailable.
但他們說可以派參謀部主任過來
But they did offer to send the Director of the Joint Staff,
明天上午11點
11:00 a.m. tomorrow.
定下來
Confirm it.
我們去白宮西樓弗蘭西斯的辦公室見
We'll meet in Francis' office at the West Wing.
還有別的事嗎
Anything else?
沒了  我該出發了
No. I should get going, hit the road.
謝謝你  康納
Thank you, Connor.
接通布魯克斯議員女士的電話
Get Congresswoman Brooks on the phone.
看看第一夫人今天下午是否有空
And see if the First Lady will be available this afternoon.
你想要給中國所有參加峰會的人做簡報嗎
You want a brief on everyone on the Chinese side of the Summit?
不  杜蘭特在華盛頓做的只是表面功夫
No. What Durant's doing in Washington is just the facade.
這可是真正的談判
This is the real negotiation.
把你手上關於馮的資料都給我
Give me what you have on Feng.
馮山德  家族在共產黨內很有影響
Xander Feng. Deep family connections to the Party.
他祖父曾跟毛澤東肩並肩作戰
Grandfather fought side by side with Mao.
在電信業勢力很大
Big in the telecom industry.
淨資產估計有五百億
Estimated net worth is over 50 billion.
比雷蒙德還有錢
More than Raymond's.
多幾十億  但誰在乎呢
By a few billion. But who's counting?
除了稀土金屬精煉廠之外
Do they have any other business partnerships
他們還有其他商業合作嗎
other than the Rare Earth Refinery?
我沒有發現
Not that I could find.
好吧  向杜蘭特詢問一下進度
All right. Get a progress update from Durant.
告訴她我們一得知馮的要求就通知她
Tell her I'll be in touch as soon as we know what Feng wants.
雷蒙德·塔斯克這樣的人涉足外交事務
When a man like Raymond Tusk gets involved in state diplomacy,
絕不是為了獲得諾貝爾和平獎
you can be sure he's not after the Nobel Peace Prize.
他是個機會主義者  但我也是
He's an opportunist. But so am I.
也許這是我的機會  能讓他放鬆對總統的控制
Maybe this is my opportunity to loosen his grip on the President.
副總統先生  你什麼時候回華盛頓
Mr. Vice President, when are you returning to Washington?
-副總統先生  你是否...  -副總統先生
- Mr. Vice President, are you... - Mr. Vice President,
你會在斯波特瑟爾韋尼亞待多久
do you have any idea how long you'll be in Spotsylvania?
對於跟中國的談判有什麼看法嗎
Any comments on the talks with the Chinese?
能否就即將到來的峰會談判發表一下看法
Can we get a comment on the upcoming Summit talks?
副總統今天
Vice President will be working
將在自己的房間裏辦公
from his room for the remainder of the day.
有消息再通知你們
We'll let you know.
先生  你什麼時候回華盛頓
Sir, when are you returning to Washington?
馮先生  很高興見到你
Mr. Feng. It's a pleasure.
彼此彼此  副總統先生
Likewise, Mr. Vice President.
喝咖啡還是喝茶
Coffee? Tea?
有人問過了  謝謝
I've already been offered, but thank you.
謝謝你  密查姆
Thank you, Meechum.
從北京飛過來時間很長
It's a long flight from Beijing.
你一定累壞了
You must be exhausted.
我一直按西方時間作息
I keep Western hours.
和你們沒有時差
My midnight is your midnight.
你已經看過計劃書了嗎
So, have you had a chance to look over the proposal?
看了
I have.
我們開始吧
Shall we?
第四頁
Page four.
精煉廠
The refinery.
與塔斯克先生合作
With Mr. Tusk.
與競標價最高的人合作
With the highest bidder.
我們準備與克雷頓-維斯特簽訂一份
We're prepared to offer Clayton West
梅梅稀土金屬精煉廠的40年租約
a 40-year lease on the Mei Mei Rare Earth Elements Refinery.
租約上會有我的名字
To which I will lend my name.
我知道你和雷蒙德是生意夥伴
I understand that you and Raymond are business associates,
但你還是得公開招標
but you're gonna have to open it up to bidding.
塔斯克先生出價肯定比其他人高
Mr. Tusk will outbid any competitors.
儘管如此  過場還是得走
Well, even so, you know, for appearances.
好吧  過場  如果你堅持
Yes. Appearances. If you must.
那這裏就沒問題了
So, there are no issues here, then?
我們繼續吧
We may proceed.
第六頁
Page six.
大橋
The bridge.
財政部外資投資管理委員會將批准
The Committee on Foreign Investment will approve
一項基礎建設示範工程
a pilot infrastructure project
建設一座從傑斐遜港到米爾福德市
to build a bridge over the Long Island Sound,
橫跨長島海峽的大橋
from Port Jefferson to Milford,
以25年的過橋收費權作為交換
in exchange for a 25-year toll-taking contract.
在我們考慮大橋前
Before we consider the bridge,
我想先討論另一件事
there's one more item I'd like to discuss.
"考慮"  我以為大橋的事已經定了
"Consider"? I thought the bridge was definite.
沒什麼是確定的
Nothing is definite.
這座大橋是首要任務
This bridge is a priority-one item.
對你們總統非常重要  我明白
It's very important to your President. I understand.
你想討論什麼
What would you like to discuss?
你們在世界貿易組織
The currency manipulation suit which
指控我們進行匯率操縱
you have filed against us in the World Trade Organization.
我們已經同意
Which we are prepared to drop
如果滿足其他條件就撤銷指控
if all other conditions are met.
我們這次會面就是為了討論
The point of this meeting is to allow us
不適合在正式場合談論的事  對嗎
to say things that cannot be said in formal settings, yes?
是的  當然
Yes. Of course.
我們不希望你們撤訴
We don't want you to drop the lawsuit.
抱歉  我
Forgive me. I...
我不明白
I don't understand.
別在世貿組織讓步
Do not back off in the WTO.
但你們在匯率操縱上
But you've been fighting us
已經和我們鬥爭多年了
on currency manipulation for years.
自由浮動匯率是大勢所趨
A free-floating currency is inevitable.
這下我有下手的空間了
Now I have something I can work with.
為什麼突然改變主意
Why the sudden change of heart?
並不突然  只是我們這些有遠見的人
Not sudden, it has taken those of us who are more forward-thinking
花了很多年才說服其他同僚
many years to convince our counterparts.
那中國直接執行就得了
But China could just do it.
你我都清楚  你們不需要世貿組織的裁定
I mean, you know as well as I, you don't require a WTO ruling.
就像你說的  得走過場
Appearances, as you say.
一定要看起來像是受美國逼迫
It's important that it looks like America forced us out,
而不是我們主動投降
not that we gave in.
那我需要時間
Well, I'll need a little more time,
去和總統商量
so that I can brief the President.
我會耐心等待
I'm here for as long as necessary.
無論你要找誰商量
However you would like to communicate,
我都不管
I leave that to you.
謝謝  副總統先生
Thank you, Mr. Vice President.
謝謝  馮先生
Thank you, Mr. Feng.
在加夫尼我們有自己的外交特色
In Gaffney we had our own brand of diplomacy:
一邊握手言歡  一邊做好準備
Shake with your right hand, but hold a rock in your left.
看看是誰困在這兒了
Well, look who got stuck with the pool.
我們來這兒簡直是找虐
We volunteered because we hate ourselves.
南方前線一切順利吧
All's well on the Southern front?
沒新聞就是沒新聞
No news is no news.
我聽說那裏還有火槍呢
Come on. I hear there's muskets out there.
你什麼時候能給我們點猛料
When you giving us something real?
我們正身處美麗的斯波特瑟爾韋尼亞
We're here in beautiful Spotsylvania, aren't we?
不過是給成年人玩玩具槍找借口
This is dress-up for grown men with toy guns.
聽起來可以寫上五百字
Sounds like 500 words to me.
告訴杜蘭特除非我們在世貿撤訴
Tell Durant that China won't discuss the bridge
否則中國不願意談大橋
unless we drop the WTO suit.
你不是說他們不希望撤訴嗎
I thought you said they want to keep it.
馮希望  說明塔斯克希望
Feng does, which means Tusk does.
但我們不知道北京是不是希望
But we don't know if Beijing does.
你覺得馮在撒謊
You think Feng's lying?
開放匯率會導致利率市場化
An open currency could free up interest rates,
減小中國的通貨膨脹
reduce inflation in China.
他們兩人都能受益
They'd both profit.
如果他們或者我們將了北京的軍
If they're forcing Beijing's hand, or we are,
可能在峰會引起混亂
that could throw the Summit into chaos.
正是  馮可能有後台支持
Exactly. Look, Feng may well have support,
但我猜常委會有分歧
but my guess is that the Standing Committee's divided.
不管怎樣  我們打他們個措手不及
Either way, we'll throw 'em off balance.
凱茜一宣佈  我們就放出撤訴的風聲
Let's leak we're dropping the suit as soon as Cathy presents it.
只是訴訟嗎  不漏點別的什麼
Just the lawsuit? Nothing else in the leak?
暗示與馮有關  但別點名
A hint of Feng, but no names.
讓消息傳一陣子再說
Let's let this grow on its own.
這回怎樣
How was that?
好多了
Much better.
我感覺不錯  你怎麼看
I feel good. What do you think?
我看你準備好了
I think you're ready.
代碼還得準備多久
How long on the code?
只差幾個漏洞了
Just a couple of bugs to work out.
我說明天或週三我就能回去
I told them tomorrow or Wednesday.
活兒還沒完
Work's not done.
我要是再往後推  你不覺得別人會奇怪嗎
If I postpone again, don't you think it'll draw attention? I --
等完事了也就沒事了
It'll be done when it's done.
漏洞修復了我就給你發郵件
I'll email you when the bugs are fixed.
挑一個公開的場所  約好時間給你
Somewhere public, a place and time.
你真想這麼做嗎
Hey, are you sure you wanna do this?
我明白風險多大
I understand the risks.
你自以為明白而已
Well, you think you do.
我也不是頭回身陷險境了
This isn't the first time I've been in danger.
是嗎  在《先驅報》被紙割傷過手嗎
Oh, yeah? Paper cuts at The Herald?
死亡威脅  我揭露了一個特區販毒集團
Death threats. When I exposed a drug ring in D.C.
我讀過你寫的報道
You know, I read the articles.
那根本不算什麼
That's small time.
我差點就接受司法保護了
I almost had to go into protection.
這可是聯調局  不是什麼街警
This is the FBI. It's not a few street cops.
你覺得自己反抗當局
You think you're badass because
就是個了不得的義士嗎
you're on some vigilante anarchy kick?
起碼我有膽子在報道上署上真實姓名
At least I have the balls to put my name on the work I do.
但你沒面臨過幾百年的刑罰
You've never faced a hundred years in prison,
你這自以為是的混蛋
you self-righteous prick.
我大多數朋友被關起來  永遠出不來
Most of my friends are locked up and rotting away
就因為他們太多次以身犯險
'cause they poked the bear one too many times.
為什麼  因為他們想揭露政府的監控項目
Why? They wanted to expose government surveillance,
棱鏡計劃  挪用公款  濫用職權  酷刑和欺騙
the PRISM program, embezzlement, abuse, fucking torture, lies.
你是個記者有什麼了不起  我們是戰士
You're a journalist. Who gives a shit? We're fucking soldiers.
這已經是我生活的一部分了
It's personal for me now.
我沒選擇了  但你還有
I don't have a choice, but you still do.
我也沒選擇了
I don't have a choice.
消息從哪來
Where did you get this?
你可以說消息源與中國代表團關係密切
You could say a source close to the Chinese delegation.
給我個名字
Give me a name.
我只知道是一個中國商人
All I know is that it's a Chinese businessman
和常委會關係非同一般  在峰會上進行秘密外交
with ties to the Standing Committee back-channeling the Summit.
-他人在華盛頓嗎  -我不知道
- In Washington? - I don't know.
-在和誰接觸  -這我也不知道
- With who? - I don't know that either.
如果我去問貿易代表處  他們會證實嗎
If I call the USTR's office, they'll confirm?
我知道多少  就告訴了你多少
I'm telling you as much as I know.
你為什麼要告訴我
Why are you telling me this at all?
反正明天他們也會把消息放出去
They're going public with it tomorrow anyway.
不如讓你搶先發佈
You might as well get the scoop.
為什麼挑中我
Why me, specifically?
內戰重演的報道配不上你這樣的記者
You deserve better than a Civil War reenactment.
別裝做你突然變成聖誕老人了
Please don't pretend you've suddenly become Santa Claus.
我現在幫你的忙  也許你會承我的情
I give you something now, maybe you'll remember.
將來有一天或許用得上
It's an investment in the future.
我可不太喜歡賣人情
I'm not big on favors.
所以我說了"也許"
I just said "maybe."
馬上給我接貿易代表處
Connect me to the USTR's office.
越過新聞發言人
Skip the Press Secretary.
跟他們說我想問世貿組織訴訟的事
Tell them I want to talk about the WTO suit.
你跟誰說了
Who did you speak to?
康納  他在向艾拉·薩伊德洩露消息
Connor. He's talking to Ayla Sayyad.
你透給他多少
How much did you fill him in?
沒說多少
The bare minimum.
要是按之前說好的
I'd be a lot more comfortable
你親自去說  我會放心許多
if it was you going directly, as we discussed.
這樣就牽涉不到我  你也就更安全了
This puts distance on me, which puts distance on you.
你今晚親自去見馮
I want you to meet with Feng tonight.
-不用中間人  -明白
- No proxies. - Understood.
古德溫先生那邊辦得如何了
Now where are we with Mr. Goodwin?
隨時可以下手  判個35年或者無期
Any day now. Thirty-five to life.
網絡恐怖主義  判刑都很重
Cyber terrorism. Penalties are stiff.
務必做得乾淨利落  道格
This needs to be clean, Doug.
會的
It will be.
一擊致命
One fall of the axe.
有消息告訴我
Keep me informed.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
我認為你的做法真是太勇敢了
Well, I just think what you did took so much bravery.
在直播節目上  當著全國觀眾的面
To go on air like that, in front of the whole country,
講出你的經歷
and say what you did?
這對我的確不容易
That means a lot to me.
我很欽佩兩位的努力  為了幫助
And I admire what you both have been doing to advocate for the –
那些受害者
well, for the victims.
是女性  就像你和我  不只是受害者
Well, women, like you and me. Not victims.
還有男人  這無關性別
Men, too. It's not gender-specific.
是啊
Well, yes.
你願意參與進來嗎
Would you consider pitching in?
怎麼參與
How?
如果有第一夫人支持  我們的表態就有力多了
It would send a strong message if we had the First Lady in our corner.
如果你覺得我能幫上忙的話
If you think I could help.
婦女黨團的領袖
Well, if the head of the Women's Caucus,
以及白宮的第一和第二夫人加起來...
both wives from the White House...
這樣的組合他們沒法無視
That's a meeting they couldn't sweep under the rug.
主席肯派人來  就已經是很好的兆頭了
And the fact that the Chairman sent anyone is promising,
但我們得保證他真能聽到我們的聲音
but we need to make sure our message gets back to him.
只是  我沒有過此類經歷
I just...I haven't been through the same sort of experience.
這有什麼妨礙呢
Well, why should that prevent you?
我不知道我是不是有發言權
I don't know if I have a right to speak about it.
你可是第一夫人
You're the First Lady.
你有權發表任何言論
You have a right to speak about anything you want.
-懷特先生  -馬博利太太
- Mr. White? - Mrs. Marbury.
叫我蘇珊
I'm Susan.
很高興見到你
Well, it's a pleasure to meet you.
我知道這裏挺偏僻的
I know I'm a little off the beaten path.
找這裏困難嗎
Did you have any trouble finding me?
不  您給的指示很明確  找起來很輕鬆
No. The directions were great. Easy as pie.
那就好
Well, good.
請進
Come in.
我得承認  我都期待一整天了
I have to admit I've been looking forward to this all day.
沒想到你們這麼快就要宣佈了
I didn't realize you were announcing so soon.
我們收到了慷慨的捐款
We've had some great luck with the endowment.
我丈夫生前沒受到多少嘉獎
Well, my husband didn't get much recognition while he was alive.
計劃生育協會想以他來命名基金
I was so thrilled when Planned Parenthood asked to
真讓我激動
name a fund after him.
您肯同意  我們也很高興
Well, we're thrilled that you're open to it.
你之前打電話說有些問題要問
When you called, you said you had some questions?
問題挺敏感的  所以我想親自來問
They're delicate. That's why I wanted to come in person.
怎麼個"敏感"法
"Delicate", how?
很多人會抗議向未成年人
There are a lot of people who will protest
提供這方面的經濟資助
this sort of financial assistance to minors.
我們得保證他們找不到誹謗我們的根據
And we want to make sure they have no cause to smear us.
我丈夫這輩子  總有人想詆毀他
People tried to smear my husband his entire career.
他從不讓這些事影響他的工作
He never let it affect the work he was doing.
您丈夫實施過任何非法墮胎手術嗎
Did your husband ever perform any illegal abortions?
我需要您的答案  馬博利太太
I need you to answer me, Mrs. Marbury.
您丈夫實施過任何非法墮胎手術嗎
Did your husband perform any illegal abortions?
我不想討論這個
I won't discuss that.
沒有未上報的嗎
Nothing unreported?
年輕人  你年紀不大  不會記得
Young man, you're not old enough to remember.
但在過去  人人...
But there was a time when everybody --
有沒有涉及什麼大人物
What about any prominent figures
能被反墮胎人士拿來當靶子的
who the Anti-Choice crowd could vilify?
沒有
No.
馬博利醫生有沒有為克萊爾·安德伍德做過墮胎
Did Dr. Marbury perform an abortion for Claire Underwood?
不  他沒有
No, he did not.
我知道他做過
I know for a fact that he did.
這是謊話  我想請你馬上離開
That is not true, and I would like you to leave now.
抱歉  馬博利太太
Forgive me, Mrs. Marbury.
我對您沒說實話
I haven't been entirely honest with you.
我叫賽斯·格雷森
My name's Seth Grayson.
我不為計劃生育協會工作
I don't work for Planned Parenthood.
馮先生
國內常委們推測  搞秘密外交的是你
華爾街電訊報
美國在世貿組織撤訴
香港出現了兩篇文章
都提到了你的名字
要我聯繫副總統嗎
不  讓他來找我
No. Let him come to me.
給塔斯克先生打電話
Get Mr. Tusk on the phone.
你真該為自己感到羞愧
You should ashamed of yourself.
我是為了你好  馬博利太太
I'm doing this for your own good, Mrs. Marbury.
想想媒體炒作的後果
Imagine the media frenzy.
您丈夫生前的名聲盡毀
Your husband's legacy, destroyed.
媒體日日夜夜追著您不放
The press hounding you, day and night.
計劃生育基金  也沒有了
And Planned Parenthood Fund, gone.
我怎麼知道你是不是為她工作
How do I know you work for her?
而不是什麼右翼狂熱分子  打算摧毀...
That you're not just some right-wing fanatic who wants to destro?
否則我就不會親自登門拜訪了
Because I wouldn't have done you the courtesy of paying a visit.
來的就不是我
There would've been an army of
而是一隊衛星轉播車了
satellite trucks at your door instead of me.
我不會告訴任何人的  如果你是擔心這個
Well, I won't tell anyone, if that's what you're worried about.
我相信您
I believe you.
您丈夫有沒有對他幫助過的女人做過任何記錄
Did your husband keep records of any kind of who he assisted?
任何東西  筆記或非公開記錄
Anything at all? Notes? Unofficial records?
他有一本日記
He kept a journal.
您還能找到嗎
Do you still have it?
我能看看嗎
May I?
看吧
Go ahead.
我得把它帶走
Oh. I need to take this with me.
你不能把那頁撕掉嗎
Can't you just take out that page?
如果有人找到這本日記  這幾頁又缺了
Someone finds this with pages missing,
那會引起懷疑
that could raise eyebrows.
這裏面有他60年的人生
There's 60 years of his life in there.
從我們相遇到他去世
From when we met until he died.
那您希望那六十年被遺忘
And do you want six decades
卻只剩下25年前8月的一個晚上嗎
reduced to one night in August...25 years ago?
想像一下這裏當時的情形
Now just imagine what it looked like back then.
山脊邊緣是茂密的灌木叢
The edge of the ridge was a dense thicket,
北方軍隊得以長驅直入  在騾子鞋列隊
which allowed the Northern troops to come in and form on the Mule Shoe.
南方軍在山脊頂端
Now the Southern regiments were entrenched
這一帶挖好了戰壕
in this area at the apex of the line.
如您所見
As you can see,
這裏的地形迫使雙方向下走  逼近彼此
the topography really forced the two sides down towards each other.
這裏就是血腥角
This is the Bloody Angle.
沒錯
That's right.
我昨晚還讀到了相關內容
I was reading about it last night.
短兵相接  白刃相見
Close quarters, hand-to-hand combat.
據說  南北雙方共有一萬五千名士兵
All told, about 15,000 Union-Confederate soldiers
在血腥角這塊半英里寬的戰場上
lost their lives here at the Bloody Angle, on a battlefield
失去了生命
that's only about half a mile wide.
副總統先生  我們今天為您準備了一份驚喜
Now, Mr. Vice President, we have a surprise for you today.
向您介紹麥高文旅第12軍團的
I'd like to introduce you to Corporal Augustus Elijah Underwood
奧古斯都·以利亞·安德伍德下士
of the 12th Regiment of the McGowan Brigade,
您的曾曾曾祖父
your great-great-great-grandfather.
我在這場戰役中犧牲於此
I died here in this battle.
我覺得是搞錯了吧
I think there's been a mistake.
我祖父從沒說過祖上有人參加過內戰
My grandfather never mentioned any Underwoods in the war.
我們做過調查
We did our research.
他就是在這裏戰鬥犧牲的
He definitely fought and died here.
我只有24歲  而我兒子
I was 24. And my son,
你的曾曾祖父只有兩歲
your great-great-grandfather was two years old.
我從沒見過他
I never met him.
就是在這裏嗎  在血腥角
It happened here, at the Bloody Angle?
在那片林子邊上
At the edge of those woods.
我的腦袋被石頭砸扁了
My skull was bashed in with a rock.
奧古斯都  謝謝你
Augustus, thank you.
這邊  還有一些
Now, uh, over here we've got something that's,
有趣的東西
uh, very interesting as well.
等一下
Uh, j—just a moment.
接著說
Tell me more.
當時正是半夜
It was the middle of the night.
我們的子彈打光了  只剩下刺刀
And we were out of musket balls, just bayonets.
而且只有一半人有刺刀  我什麼都沒有
Only half of us had those. I had nothing.
只能靠這雙手
Just these hands.
天很黑  什麼都看不見
So dark, couldn't see nothing.
但能聽北方佬在朝我們跑來
But you could hear 'em, the Yanks, runnin' toward us.
接著就能聞到他們了
And then you could smell 'em.
我遇到的第一個北方佬
First Yank that brushed up against me,
被我掐住了脖子  倒在地上
I grab him by the throat, fall down on the ground.
我用力打他  打到皮開肉綻
I bit him so hard, I could taste the bone.
然後他抓起一塊石頭  砸中了這裏
Then he grabs a rock and brings it down right here.
我就這麼死了
And that was that.
我被埋在萬人冢裏  沒有墓碑
I was buried in a mass grave, no headstone.
能給您和奧古斯都拍張合影嗎
Could we get a picture with you and Augustus?
好
Yes.
謝謝你
Thank you.
他相當認真啊
He takes it rather seriously.
是啊  他們都很認真
Oh, yeah. They all do.
前面有我們重建的
Now, up ahead, we have examples of,
邦聯軍壁壘的模型
uh, Confederate ramparts that we've reconstructed.
可以看到他們是如何伐木挖戰壕的
And you can see how they cut the timber and made the trenches.
在戰鬥過程中
Now these trenches traded hands
這些戰壕幾次易手
many times over the course of the battle.
你有鑰匙
You have keys.
你歸我們管  沒錯  我們有鑰匙
We own you. Yes, we have keys.
我去把衣服穿上
I'm gonna put some clothes on.
別想衣服的事了
Forget your clothes.
你的原話"你真想這麼做嗎"
And I quote, "You sure you wanna do this?"
"我沒選擇了  但你還有"
And I quote, "I don't have a choice, but you do."
你他媽以為自己在幹什麼
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
他應該知道他究竟要做什麼
He should know what he's getting into.
這是絲綢睡褲嗎
Are those silk pajamas?
近距離看更有檔次了
Looks even fancier in person.
腰果
Cashew.
不  別碰她
No. Don't touch her.
過來  小傢伙
Hey, there, little guy.
我以前在監控裏見過你
I've seen you before on camera, hmm?
請把她放下
Please put her down.
不要冒險
Don't take the chance.
這這雙鞋是在彭尼百貨公司買的
I bought these shoes at J.C. Penney,
含稅價72塊
$72 with tax.
橡膠鞋底  用水就能沖乾淨
Rubber soles. You can clean 'em off with a hose.
求求你  你弄傷她了
Please, you're hurting her.
我也有一隻寵物  他叫嘉文·奧爾西
I have a pet, too. His name is Gavin Orsay.
坐下
Sit.
我說"坐下"
I said, "Sit."
瞧瞧你多乖呀  嘉文
Look what a good boy you are, Gavin.
你想讓我這麼做嗎
Is that what you need me to do?
安靜  我說"去撿"  你就去
Quiet. When I say "fetch," you fetch.
現在我們去抓盧卡斯  就像我們說好的那樣
And now we are going to fetch Lucas, just like we discussed.
你要是敢咬我  我就殺了你
If you try to bite my hand, I will put you to sleep.
介意我拿兩瓶嗎
Mind if I take a couple?
道格·斯坦普  我是副總統的幕僚長
Doug Stamper, I'm the Vice President's Chief of Staff.
我知道  坐吧
I know. Sit down.
我祖父參加過革命
My grandfather fought in the Revolution.
中國當時很窮
China was poor, then.
很難買到糖
Sugar was hard to come by.
現在中國到處能買到糖
Now sugar's everywhere in China.
要來杯古典雞尾酒嗎
Do you like Old-Fashioneds?
不  謝謝
No, thanks.
我看到新聞了
I've seen the news.
你們政府對我們撤訴非常高興
Your government was enthusiastic about our dropping the suit.
他們還在國內將其鼓吹為一場勝利
They've touted it as a victory back home.
確實是勝利  但不是我們想要的勝利
It is a victory, but not the victory we wanted.
這讓我們很難相信
We're finding that difficult to believe.
你說我們  是指副總統吧
By "we," you mean the Vice President.
我指的是美國政府
I mean the American government.
他聲稱自己就代表美國政府
Which he proclaims to represent.
沒錯  而我代表他
He does. And I'm representing him.
斯坦普先生  別吹噓你的地位
Don't inflate your status, Mr. Stamper.
你不過是個跑腿的
You're nothing but an errand boy.
你要對副總統說什麼嗎
Do you have a message for the Vice President?
如果他代表美國政府
If he represents the American government,
那他為什麼沒能轉達我的要求
then why did he fail to communicate my request?
我們質疑你的合法性  馮先生
We question your legitimacy, Mr. Feng.
你們代表團的做法和言論
Nothing your delegation has done or said has,
都與你的要求背道而馳
in any way, supported your requests.
聞聞
Smell that.
我用了高檔珍稀的麥卡倫
I use Macallan Rare and Fine,
1926年產  一瓶四萬美金
1926. $40,000 a bottle.
你以前酗酒  是嗎
You used to be an alcoholic, correct?
酒癮是戒不掉的  只能克制
Not "used to be." Still am. A sober one.
你懷念這味道嗎
Do you miss it?
那可是五千美元
Five thousand dollars you just spilled.
我會寄張支票給你
I'll send you a check.
我喜歡你  斯坦普先生  即便你只是個跑腿的
I like you, Mr. Stamper, even if you're just an errand boy.
我再問你一次
I'll ask you again.
你要對副總統說什麼嗎
What is your message for the Vice President?
恢復起訴  否則傑斐遜港大橋項目將取消
There will be no Port Jefferson Bridge unless the lawsuit is reintroduced.
到時  常委會會有人抗議
When you do, there will be those on the Standing Committee who protest,
我會搞定他們
but I'll manage them.
大多數人想要改革
The majority want reform.
我會告訴副總統
I'll tell the Vice President.
斯坦普先生  還有一條
Mr. Stamper, one more message.
請提醒副總統  我們來這裏
Please remind the Vice President that we are both here
是應我們共同的朋友塔斯克先生的邀請
at the behest of our mutual friend, Mr. Tusk.
如果副總統不願意合作  我就直接跳過他
If the Vice President fails to cooperate, I will simply bypass him.
怎麼了
Yes?
是道格
It's Doug.
好吧
Fine.
跟馮談了
Spoke with Feng.
給你的洋蔥圈
Here's your onion rings.
你知道朗斯特裏特將軍就是在這裏
Did you know that General Longstreet was shot here,
被他自己人意外誤傷害死的
accidentally, by his own men in the dark?
不  我不知道
No...I didn't.
好吧  跟我介紹一下進展吧
All right. Bring me up to date.
跟馮談得怎麼樣了
Where are we with Feng?
他要我們恢復訴訟
He wants us to resume the lawsuit.
看來他要堅持立場
So, he's sticking to his guns.
我們不起訴  大橋項目就取消
If we don't reintroduce it, there's no bridge project.
那樣總統會很失望
Well, that would greatly upset the President.
要我轉達馮的意思嗎
Do you want me to deliver Feng's message?
絕對不要
Absolutely not.
我們就要讓總統生氣
We want the President angry.
不過要想辦法不讓他怪罪在我身上
The tricky part is making sure he doesn't direct it toward me.
那你要我做什麼
So what do you want me to do?
聯繫凱茜的人
Get a hold of Cathy's people.
決不能提及訴訟
Do not mention the lawsuit at all.
讓他們自己提大橋項目
Have them bring up the bridge instead.
看看馮是不是在虛張聲勢
Let's see if Feng is bluffing.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
得吸取朗斯特裏特的教訓  他樹大招風
We must learn from Longstreet. He rode too high in the saddle.
如果明天有人朝我開槍
If a bullet comes my way tomorrow,
那絕不會是意外  而且我得趕快躲開
it will not be an accident, and I must be quick to duck.
先生們  感謝你們的到來
Gentlemen, thank you for coming.
副總統會出席嗎
Is the Vice President attending?
不會  他不在華盛頓
No, he's not. He's out of town.
我只是決定用他的辦公室
I just decided to use his office
因為他的比我的大得多
because it's a bit bigger than mine.
請坐吧
Please, sit.
我知道這不是你們第一次
I know this isn't the first conversation
談性侵犯的問題
you've had about sexual assault.
我們和議員女士
We've had a very open dialogue
已經進行了一段時間的公開對話了
with the Congresswoman for quite some time.
可以說"公開"
"Open" is one way to put it.
我倒覺得參謀長聯席會議只是在默默忍受我
I think the Joint Chiefs have tolerated my concerns, but
公平來講  我們一直有做出積極回應
To be fair, we've been quite responsive.
過去兩年裏...
Over the past two years alone, we --
議員女士對我表達了她的沮喪
The Congresswoman has expressed her frustration to me
因為這件事上仍有改進空間
that there's still room for improvement.
安德伍德夫人  我能說幾句嗎
Mrs. Underwood, if I may.
請講
Please.
這件事我們十分看重
This is an issue we've grappled with seriously.
我們增加了相關教育和防範措施
Increased education and prevention measures,
整改匯報流程
restructuring the reporting process,
杜絕軍事法庭的濫用職權現象
insulating courts martial from abuse of power.
但還是不夠
It's still not enough.
我們不會進行民事審判的
Civilian jurisdiction is not gonna happen.
我們都清楚這是議員女士所希望的
We're all aware that's what the Congresswoman would prefer,
但我們不會允許我們...
but we won't allow our cha--
我遲到了嗎
Am I late?
是我的錯  會面提前了
It's my fault. The meeting got pushed up.
我本想給你發郵件的  非常抱歉
I meant to email you. I'm very sorry.
沒關係  請坐
That's fine. Please, sit.
我們不知道您也會來  沃剋夫人
We didn't know you'd be attending, Mrs. Walker.
抱歉打斷你們了
I'm sorry for interrupting.
請繼續
Continue.
正如我剛剛所說
As I was saying,
將性侵案件的審判權完全交給民事法庭
putting sexual assault cases entirely in the hands of civilian courts
從根本上侵蝕了軍隊自我約束的能力
fundamentally erodes the military's ability to self-discipline.
那要是實施民事監管  而不是民事法庭呢
What about civilian oversight instead of civilian courts?
任何讓步  都會一發不可收拾
That's a slippery slope.
對於種族融合  也曾有人說過類似的話
There were those who said the same about racial integration.
融合沒有改變核心的運作本質...
Integration didn't change the core operational nature of the --
但的確證明了軍方可以實現自我改革
But it did prove that the military could shape its own evolution.
那是沒錯  但就這個問題
Absolutely. But in this case,
民事監管不是解決辦法
civilian oversight is not the answer.
我丈夫沒有軍銜  但他監管軍方
My husband is a civilian who oversees the military.
你難道想說
Are you suggesting that
民眾在這種問題上無從提供指導嗎
civilians can offer no guidance in matters like this?
抱歉  沃剋夫人  我完全不是那個意思
Forgive me, Mrs. Walker. I didn't mean to suggest that at all.
那或許你該聽聽你對面的民眾是怎麼想的
Then maybe you should listen to the civilian sitting across from you.
當然  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
這是你們出版的性侵防範讀物
This is from your own sexual assault prevention literature.
上面寫道  有些情況下
And in it, it says in some cases
更應該屈從  而不是抵抗
it may be advisable to submit than to resist.
所以我想  這方面顯然還有可以改進的地方
I think it's quite clear that there's still room for improvement.
你知道馮山德嗎
Did you know about Xander Feng?
在新聞上看到才知道的
Not 'til I saw his name on the wire.
美聯社  路透社等大新聞通訊社發佈的新聞  媒體獲得後會進行轉載
他曾兩次被指控腐敗
He's been charged with corruption twice.
兩次指控都撤銷了
Both times the charges were dropped.
你知道在中國獲罪後會怎樣嗎
Do you know what happens in China if you're convicted?
-我猜不會有好事  -判死刑
- I'm guessing it's not good. - You die.
我說對了
There you go.
這人如果再上"過場法庭"
We're talking about a man who's only one kangaroo court
指完全是擺擺樣子的法庭  根本不會認真按照法律進行審判
就必死無疑
away from lethal injection,
而且他富可敵國  腐敗昭然若揭
who's filthy rich and clearly corrupt.
中方就派這樣的人來嗎
And this is who the Chinese send?
你問錯人了
You're asking the wrong guy.
別再躲躲閃閃了
Stop dodging.
我不過是傳了個話  僅此而已
I passed a note in class. That's all.
我們信任你  弗蘭克
We placed our faith in you, Frank.
我們還有今明兩天時間  總統先生
We still have the rest of the day and all of tomorrow, Mr. President.
我需要這座橋
I need this bridge.
否則我的基建項目就得叫停
Otherwise, we have to stall my infrastructure program.
沒有外國投資  沒法削減赤字
No foreign investment, no deficit reduction.
中方知道這一點
And the Chinese know this.
他們就是拿這個做籌碼
They're using it for leverage.
但是為了什麼呢
Yeah, but for what?
我也不清楚
Well, that I'm not sure of.
那我們派你去斯波特瑟爾韋尼亞幹什麼  弗蘭克
Then why did we send you to Spotsylvania, Frank?
這些問題你該心裏有數的
You're supposed to have answers to these questions.
總統先生  我一小時前和馮先生聯繫過
Mr. President, I spoke to Mr. Feng an hour ago.
他怎麼說
What'd he say?
子彈來了
Here comes the bullet.
他說弗蘭克沒表達清楚他的意思
He claims that Frank hasn't been delivering his messages properly.
我已經逐字複述了他的要求
I have conveyed his requests word for word.
他說  你一直在唱反調
He says you've been doing the opposite.
究竟是誰在負責私下溝通  我還是雷蒙德
Whose responsible for the back-channeling here, me or Raymond?
你  弗蘭克
You are, Frank.
我只是來幫忙的  不是來談判的
I'm simply here to facilitate, not negotiate.
可你還繼續私下聯繫
And yet you continue to have private conversations with
北京所謂的密使
Beijing's supposed emissary.
聽著  弗蘭克
Listen, Frank --
你要信任馮先生  而不是我嗎  雷蒙德
Are you prepared to trust Mr. Feng's word over mine, Raymond?
沒人質疑你的話  弗蘭克
No one is doubting your word, Frank.
如果馮真的是為了他政府的利益
Well, if Feng is truly representing his government's interest,
為什麼他在我這兒一套  雷蒙德那兒一套
then why is he telling Raymond one thing and telling me another?
那大橋項目取消是怎麼回事
How do you explain the bridge falling through?
自由浮動匯率能讓他受益
Well, he personally profits from a free-floating currency,
和他合作的人都是如此
just as anyone would who's in business with him,
就比如你  雷蒙德
such as yourself, Raymond.
精煉廠和大橋是兩碼事
The refinery and the bridge are two completely different issues.
我們先說橋的事
Let's keep our focus, here.
必須重談建橋的事  沒得商量
I want the bridge back on the table, end of story.
-凱瑟琳  -我明早第一個提這件事
- Catherine? - It'll be the first item I bring up in the morning.
弗蘭克  先按兵不動  別聯繫馮
Frank, stay put for now. But don't contact Feng.
你也是  雷蒙德
And that goes for you, too, Raymond.
建橋的事談妥之前不許你們再私下會面
I don't want any more back-channeling until the bridge is revived.
凱瑟琳  有什麼事直接和我說
And, Catherine, you communicate directly with me.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
那就先說到這裏了
All right. We're done here.
第一滴血濺了出來
The first drops of blood have been spilt.
子彈擦過我的臉頰  但我沒有倒下
Bullet grazed my cheek, but I haven't fallen.
道格  想個辦法讓我見到馮
Doug, find me a way to meet Feng.
有件事我們得先談談
We need to discuss something first.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
我剛跟一個叫賽斯·格雷森的人通了電話
I just got off the phone with a guy named Seth Grayson.
我和我丈夫聊過了
I've spoken with my husband.
道格說了  感謝你能見我
Doug told me. Thank you for fitting me in today.
-是這個吧  -86年8月
- Is that it? - August '86.
我們憑什麼相信你
And why should we trust you?
有些證據康納沒能抹去
There was evidence that Connor didn't make disappear.
我本可以把這個拿給《美國週刊》
I could've taken this to Us Weekly
報酬夠我買新房了
and bought a new house.
可我把它帶來給您
Instead, I brought it to you.
我當時面試的時候你為什麼沒申請
And why didn't you apply when I was interviewing candidates?
申請了也沒用  薇拉不喜歡我
There's no point. Willa doesn't like me.
她怕我
I intimidate her.
這日記就是我的簡歷
That journal is my version of a resume.
或是勒索信
Or extortion.
我沒想勒索您  安德伍德夫人
I'm not extorting you, Mrs. Underwood.
我只是想強調
I'm just highlighting the difference
好的決定和正確決定的差別
between a good choice and the right choice.
那你說解雇剛聘用三個月的媒體主管
And tell me, how would we handle the repercussions
所帶來的影響我們要怎麼應對
of firing our comm director three months after we hire him.
您不用解雇他
You don't fire him.
您告訴他僱用我是為了減輕工作量
You tell him that you're bringing me on board to help with the workload.
他還負責您  我負責您丈夫
He stays on with you. I cover your husband.
康納不會喜歡和我合作的
Connor will hate working with me.
過幾個月我再找人來挖他牆角
I'll arrange a job offer elsewhere in a few months.
到那時  他會願意接受的
By the time it comes in, he'll want to move on.
康納也知道  如何保證他不會公開
Connor knows. What's to prevent him from going public?
我能搞定康納·埃利斯
I can handle Connor Ellis.
您只能相信我  我...
You just have to take me on my word on that. I –
我只知道
Here's what I know.
您要弄垮我比我扳倒您容易得多
It is far easier for you to destroy me than the other way around.
我得和我丈夫談談
I have to speak to my husband.
沒問題
Of course.
我沒有複印
I didn't make any copies.
您手上的是唯一的一份
You have the only one.
純尊尼獲加黑牌
Uh, Johnny Walker Black, neat.
-東西在哪  -我口袋裏
- Where is it? - It's in my pocket.
給我吧
Come on.
-有問題嗎  -沒有  一切就緒
- Something up? - No. We're good to go.
你看起來很緊張
You seem nervous.
雖然我干了二十年違法亂紀的事
Just because I've been breaking the law for 20 years
我還是會覺得緊張
doesn't mean I don't still get nervous.
-嘉文  -別說我的名字
- Gavin. - Do not say my name.
看著我
Look at me.
沒問題的  我們練習過了
It's gonna be fine. We practiced.
我有信心  會成功的
I'm confident. This is gonna work.
我請你
I got your drink.
他非常有資歷
He's more than qualified.
你的直覺怎麼說
What do your instincts tell you?
我不想再增加曝光度了
That I just don't wanna end up more exposed.
格雷森都知道了
Well, Grayson already knows.
我們要是不表現出...
I mean, if we don't exhibit some degree of --
讓道格去查查他
Have Doug look into him.
看看我們有沒有籌碼
Let's see if there's some leverage.
但是我們不知道他能查到什麼
Yeah, but we don't know what he'll find
什麼時候能查到  這期間格雷森又會做什麼
or when,  or what he'll do in the meantime.
這讓我們無從防備
And that puts us into unchartered territory.
如果我們解雇康納  他也會告密的
Well, Connor will expose us, too, if we let him go.
處理得好就不會
Not if it goes smoothly.
如果現在拒絕格雷森  我們無法預料後果
If we turn away Grayson now, we can't predict anything.
而且他可比我們要輸得起
And, look, he has a lot less to lose than we do.
好吧  我只是不相信他  弗蘭西斯
Okay. I just – I don't think we can trust him, Francis.
如果康納盡了職我們也不會有這麻煩了
We wouldn't be having this conversation if Connor had done his job.
我寧可要個不可信任的手下
And I'd rather manage someone I don't trust
也不要做事不周到的
than someone who is reckless.
好吧  下一步怎麼做
Fine. What's the next step?
我先親自跟格雷森談談
I'd like to talk to Grayson myself first,
然後我讓道格跟康納談談
and then I'll have Doug talk to Connor.
你那邊怎麼樣
How are you doing?
你關注新聞了嗎
You been following the news?
對我們來說是好是壞
Is it bad for us? Or good?
都有可能
Could go either way.
需要我的話就開口
I'm here if you need me.
我明天就回去
I'm back tomorrow.
-我愛你  -我也愛你
- I love you. - Love you, too.
-都準備好了嗎  -都準備好了  先生
- We all set? - All set, sir.
走吧
Let's go.
不  把燈關掉
Oh, no, no. Turn those off.
把燈關掉
Turn those off.
他在哪
Where is he?
這邊走  先生
Right this way, sir.
奧古斯都會拉小提琴嗎
Did Augustus play?
我希望我會
I like to think I did.
你自己的名字是什麼
What's your own name?
我在這裏的時候  我就是奧古斯都·安德伍德
When I'm here, I'm Augustus Underwood.
你的真名是什麼
What's your real name?
你覺得這不真實嗎
Doesn't this feel real to you?
你能帶我去看他死的地方嗎  具體地點
Will you show me where he died? The exact spot.
好的  先生
I will, sir.
我要去向我的祖先致敬
I'm gonna pay respects to my ancestor.
請給我點隱私
I would appreciate a little privacy.
我們在這裏等著
We'll wait here.
小約翰在移動
Little John on the move.
就在那些樹後
Just beyond those trees.
謝謝你  我自己過去吧
Thank you. I'll be good from here.
沒事
We're fine.
希望你沒等太久
I hope you haven't waited long.
這裏很平靜  我不介意
It's peaceful here. I didn't mind.
現在很平靜  但有一萬五千人曾在這裏喪生
Peaceful now. Fifteen thousand men died in these woods.
我的曾曾曾祖父死在我們站的地方
My grandfather's grandfather died where we're standing.
我的祖父在革命中犧牲
My grandfather was killed in the Revolution.
我聽說了
So I've heard.
你怕死嗎  副總統先生
Do you fear death, Mr. Vice President?
跟其他人一樣
No more or less than any man.
死亡給我激勵  讓我去經歷一切
It motivates me. To experience everything,
在一切化為糞土之前  努力成就偉業
accomplish all I can before it all vanishes.
在這方面我覺得我們很像
I think you and I are similar in that regard.
那我們為什麼要彼此背道而馳呢
Then why are we working at cross purposes?
你的意思是
Now what you mean is,
為什麼我不服從你和塔斯克先生
"Why am I not submitting to you and Mr. Tusk?"
你在破壞談判
You're sabotaging the negotiations.
而你在利用談判達到自己的目的
And you're using them for your own personal ends.
錯了  我花了七年時間說服常委
Wrong. It's taken me seven years to convince the Standing Committee
這才是應該採取的做法
that this was the right course of action.
可以給你和塔斯克帶來數十億收益的做法
A course of action that will earn you and Tusk billions.
你約我在這裏見面就為了攻擊我嗎
Why did you want this meeting? Just to attack me?
為了給雷蒙德帶個信
To send a message to Raymond.
美國總統和我不是他的傀儡
The President of the United States and I are not his puppets.
你就這麼跟他說
Now you tell him that.
好  橋的事沒戲了  沒有挽回餘地
Fine. The bridge deal is dead. There will be no saving it.
隨你怎麼折騰吧
Stick a knife through its heart and put an apple in its mouth.
我才不在乎呢
I won't shed a tear.
你們總統會把失敗歸咎於你
Your President will ascribe the failure to you.
我願意冒這個險
I'll take the risk.
好好想想  副總統先生
Think strategically, Mr. Vice President.
你這是把我們往絕路上推
You're setting us on a very dangerous course.
你知道格蘭特將軍是如何擊敗李將軍的嗎
Do you know how Grant defeated Lee?
他的人更多  僅此而已
He had more men. That's all.
而且他願意讓他們去送死
And he was willing to let them die.
是屠殺  而非策略  贏得了戰爭
It was butchery, not strategy, which won the war.
塔斯克先生和我有豐厚資源可以利用
Mr. Tusk and I have great resources at our disposal.
把你們的錢加起來
Add up all your billions together,
相當於斯洛伐克的國內生產總值
and you get the GDP of Slovakia.
我背後是美利堅合眾國的聯邦政府
I have the federal government of the United States of America.
你們的錢嚇不倒我
Your money doesn't intimidate me.
你最多能買到影響力
The most that you can buy is influence.
但我可以利用憲法施壓
But I wield Constitutional authority.
最強大的軍隊並不總是能取勝
The strongest army doesn't always win.
毛主席從幾千人的軍隊起步
Mao started out with only a few thousand men.
最終打下了半個亞洲
They took over half a continent.
毛主席已經死了  他的中國也死了
Mao is dead. And so is his China.
但我沒死
But I'm not.
目前還沒有
Not yet.
別忘了  你的祖先為戰敗的一方而戰
Don't forget. Your ancestor fought for the losing side.
成者王  敗者寇
There is no sacred ground for the conquered.
我們這裏有九千餘台服務器  分屬幾百家客戶
We have over 9,000 servers here, utilized by several hundred clients.
從小企業到大公司都有
Everything from small businesses to major corporations.
最大的客戶都有誰
What are some of the largest clients?
這裏最大的是美國電話電報公司
The largest here is AT&T.
他們的服務器佔了這層大半的空間
Their servers occupy more than half of the floor space.
能讓我看看嗎
And can you show me?
當然
I am.
這邊走
Right this way.
你昨晚有沒有去見馮
Did you or did you not meet with Feng last night?
這話從何說起  雷蒙德
Where is this coming from, Raymond?
回答我  弗蘭克
Answer the question, Frank.
上次談話後我就沒聯繫過他了  總統先生
I have not contacted him since you and I spoke, Mr. President.
完全按照您的要求
Just as you instructed me to do.
馮可不是這麼說的
Not according to Feng.
你不是也不許見他嗎  雷蒙德
I believe you were also instructed to avoid him too, Raymond.
他自己找上門來的  我只是接了電話
He reached out to me. I just answered the call.
我們事先有明確的協議  弗蘭克
We had clear, prearranged terms, frank.
私下接觸了數月
Months of back-channeling.
我在第一線  總統先生
I am on the front lines, Mr. President.
我的親身體會是
And I can tell you firsthand
我們現在面對的這個國家
that we are dealing with a regime
不僅有事隱瞞
that is not being forthright and
而且會利用任何風吹草動
will seize upon the faintest whiff of trepidation.
這是次考驗
This is a test.
看我們被逼到什麼境地會投降
To see how far they can push us before we break.
別讓他們得逞  中止談判
Do not play their game. End the talks.
我們不能反應過度
We can't overreact here.
他們中止了商貿聯委會的談判
Well, they walked away from the Joint Commission.
我們也可以中止峰會
We can walk away from the Summit.
經濟損失難以估量  市場會
The economic fallout would be catastrophic. The market would--
要麼向這個新興超級大國卑躬屈膝也行
Or we can just kowtow and submit to the new reigning superpower.
別誇大其詞  弗蘭克
Don't be hyperbolic, Frank.
我們可是在跟全球四分之一的人口打交道
Well, we are dealing with one quarter of the world's population.
總統先生  這會釀成大錯的
Mr. President, you would be making a disastrous mistake.
你到底效忠誰  雷蒙德
Where are your allegiances, Raymond?
是馮山德還是美國
With Xander Feng or to the United --?
你怎麼敢質疑我的
Don't you dare question me about --
行了  安靜
All right. Silence.
我犯了兩個錯誤
There were two mistakes. Both of them mine.
第一個錯誤是允許你  雷蒙德
The first was allowing you, Raymond,
讓你的商業夥伴參與談判
to enlist your business partner for these talks.
我只是想
I was simply trying to --
而第二個錯誤就是讓你去  弗蘭克
And the second was enlisting you, Frank.
不但沒把話說清楚
Instead of clarity,
還造成誤解  外交表現糟糕
we got miscommunication. That's poor diplomacy.
總統先生  聽我說
Mr. President, listen --
不  你們的話我都聽過了
Oh, no. I've listened. To both of you.
但只聽到了互相譴責
And all I've heard is accusations.
如果你們誰都不願負責  那我來
Now if neither of you will take responsibility, I will.
我們撤出
We're pulling out.
並非是聽從你的意見  弗蘭克
That's not because you suggested it, Frank.
而是因為你協商失敗
It's because you've made such a mess of these negotiations
讓我不得不表現出強硬態度
that I have no other choice than a show of strength.
你們兩個都讓我很失望
You've both disappointed me greatly.
總統先生
Mr. President --
總統已離線
The President has left the call.
雷蒙德  你還在嗎
Raymond, are you still there?
這是他二十年來第一次
That's the first time he's ever hung up on me
掛我電話
in 20 years.
為你難過
Oh. I feel for you.
再見  弗蘭克
Goodbye, Frank.
現在  殺戮開始
And the butchery begins.
從這排起  到後面七排全是
It's all the way down this row and the next seven rows over.
你想進去看看  是吧
Now you wanted to see inside one, right?
是  那就太好了
Yeah, that would be great.
進去吧
Go ahead.
其實沒什麼好看的
There's not much to it, actually.
就是一堆硬盤和電線
Just a lot of hard drives and wires.
說到文件備份  如果突然停電
So in terms of back-up, if the power goes down,
比如碰上自然災害
some natural disaster hits,
龍捲風或地震之類的  要怎麼
like a storm, or an earthquake, what exactly --?
-趴在地上  -不許動
- On the ground. - Freeze!
-不  我  -立刻趴下
- No, no, I  - right now.
-趴下  立刻趴下  -我說了趴下
- On the ground! On the ground now! - I said on the fucking ground.
跟我同車回特區吧
Why don't you ride back to D.C. with me?
我們有事要談
We need to discuss something.
怎麼了
What's up?
我們車裏談
We'll talk about it in the car.
今天  我們在陸路戰役遊客中心破土動工
Today, we break earth on the Overland Campaign Visitors Center.
這樣我們的後代
So that generations to come
能深刻體會這片聖地的重要意義
will fully absorb the importance of this hallowed ground,
銘記這片戰役打響的荒野
the wilderness where the campaign commenced.
奧古斯都  請你來好嗎
Augustus. Would you do the honor?
請為逝者默哀祈禱
And now a moment of silence and prayer for the dead.
謝謝各位
Thank you.
天祐美國
And God bless the United States of America.
剛收到消息
I just heard.
我們抓到盧卡斯·古德溫了
We got Lucas Goodwin.
"人民幣被刻意低估"是長期困擾中美經貿關係的一個焦點議題
多年來  美國國會一直指責中國政府刻意壓低人民幣幣值
使中國產品價格低廉  出口後佔據價格優勢
許多議員將美國的對華的巨大貿易逆差  美國國內製造業的蕭條
均歸咎於人民幣幣值的被低估
在這個問題上立場最強硬的是國會中的民主黨議員
他們背後大多有美國工會的支持
很多議員家鄉有大量從事製造業的選民
過去這些年  美國國會通過聽證會和立法等多種形式
向中國政府施壓  該問題也是中美經濟事務會談爭論的焦點
但白宮在匯率問題上的立場要軟得多
小布什政府一直頂住國會的壓力  拒絕將中國政府列為"匯率操縱國"
奧巴馬雖然在競選時接受了工會的巨額捐款
但上任後也沒有在這個問題上滿足國會的強硬要求
白宮非常清楚地認識到  如果在這一問題上同中國硬碰硬
導致貿易戰  其結果將是兩敗俱傷
所以本屆美國政府一直拒絕公開將中國列為"匯率操縱國"
2005年中國進行匯率改革之後  人民幣一直穩中有升
中美之間的匯率問題也逐漸降溫  一些美國智庫的專家認為
即使美國現在決定到世貿組織就這一問題向中國提起訴訟
比起5年前來  勝訴的可能性也非常之小